PHILLIP PATTERSON

EMAIL: phillip.s.patterson1@gmail.com **WEBSITE:** philpatterson.io **PHONE:** (802)373-4015 **LINKEDIN:** /in/philpatt/ **GITHUB:** philpatt

SUMMARY

My years of experience in analytical science has strengthened my attention to detail, problem solving and reinforced the necessary soft-skills needed for a collaborative environment. I have a desire to grow and continuously learn to strengthen my passion of creating for others. I am drawn to web development because I enjoy bringing a vision to life, whether it be my own or from a client.

PROJECTS

Team Manager

- HTML 5, CSS 3, Django, Python 3, PostgreSQL.
- Using the Django built-in administration site to manage custom relational databases that help manage Maine Mussels Youth Lacrosse Organization and to create custom front-end displays .

Teddi

- HTML 5, CSS 3, Javascript, jQuery, PostgreSQL, RESTful API/AJAX, Node, and Express
- This app allows you to access the National Park Service's API and save up to date information about all the US National Parks

Connect 4

- HTML 5, CSS 3, Javascript, jQuery
- Based off the common childhood game, Connect 4, two players play against each other, alternating turns, to get 4 game pieces in a row (horizontal, vertical, or horizontal)

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, Full-Stack Web Developer

Nov 2017 - Mar 2018

- Spent 700+ hours in collaborative project-based web development course, focused on full stack application with rigorous deadlines
- Highly focused on the implementation of the MERN stack with exposure to ReactJS, Python, and Django
- Highly efficient in using Git workflow version control and white-boarding design techniques to complete deliverables in 1 week sprints

Aspenti Health, Data Review and Confirmation Scientist, Burlington, Vermont Aug 2016 - Nov 2017

- Established new employee work schedule that increased specimen turn around time by 50%
- Collected and processed data acquired from analytical instrumentation
- Troubleshoot instrumentation and investigate aberrant results
- Performed routine maintenance and troubleshooting of equipment

Mylan Technologies, Quality Control Analytical Chemist, St. Albans, Vermont Aug 2014 - Aug 2016

- Performed analytical testing on all of Mylan Technology pharmaceutical transdermal products (12 different patches in varied doses)
- Short term(1 hour) and long term(1 month) analysis of transdermal patches, which increased delivery of product quality
- Interpreted test results and ensured that they met specifications and performed analytical investigations to address aberrant results

SKILLS

FRONT-END: HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Express

BACK-END: PostgreSQL, Node JS

TECHNICAL: Git / GitHub, Wire Framing, Web-Scraping (Cheerio)

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Web Development 2018

12 week immersive Web Development Program

Castleton University

BA Health Science 2013

ACTIVITIES

Castleton Men's Lacrosse

Aug 2009 - May 2013

Nominated Captain in 2013